Program Records, 1982-2002
Smithsonian Institution Archives
Program Records
1982-2002
Smithsonian Institution Archives, Washington, D.C., osiaref@si.edu
National Museum of American History, Program in African American Culture
SI Records
1.5 cu. ft. (1 record storage box) (1 document box)
Accession 05-116
Descriptive Entry
This accession consists of records of the Program in African American Culture (PAAC) which document planning for conferences, symposiums, concerts, and special events. Some earlier records date back to when PAAC was known as the Program in African American History and the Program in Black American Culture, respectively. Materials include correspondence, memoranda, and notes of Niani Kilkenny, PAAC Director; and Victoria Botero, Conference Coordinator. Also includes meeting minutes, budget summaries, press releases, research information, evaluations, contracts, program proposals, and reports.
Index Terms
This collection is indexed under the following access terms. These are links to collections with related topics, persons or places.
Name
Kilkenny, Niani.; Botero, Victoria.; National Museum of American History (U.S.). Program in African American History.; National Museum of American History (U.S.). Program in Black American Culture.
Subject
African Americans; Conference proceedings; Contracts
Physical Characteristics of Materials in the Collection
Manuscripts; Brochures; Floppy disks; Black-and-white transparencies; Black-and-white photographs
- Box 1
  - Middle Passage Conference: Advisory Meeting Notes, 1998 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Middle Passage Conference: Participants/Contact List, 1998 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Middle Passage Conference (general), 1998 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Deborah Mack, 1998 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Lifetime Achievement Awards, 1999 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Photographs and Images, 1999 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Middle Passage Conference: Flyers, 1998 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Middle Passage Conference: Films, 1999 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Middle Passage Conference: Correspondence, 1998-1999 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Middle Passage Conference: Newspaper Clippings, 1998 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Adelaide Cromwell, 1998-1999 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Middle Passage Conference: Abstracts, 1998-1999 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Middle Passage Conference: Budget, 1999 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Middle Passage Conference: Biographies, 1998-1999 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Trans-Atlantic Slave Trade, 1998 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Middle Passage Conference: Advisory Committee Correspondence, 1998-1999 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Articles on Curtis Mayfield, 2001-2002 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Pictures of Curtis Mayfield, 2002 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Curtis Mayfield Symposium, 2001 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Curtis Mayfield Research, 2002 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Curtis Mayfield Symposium: Contact List, 2002 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Curtis Mayfield Symposium: Budget, 2001 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Another Day's Journey: Contacts, 2000-2001 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Another Day's Journey: Security, 2001 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Another Day's Journey: Press Releases, 2001 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Another Day's Journey: Flyer Information, 2000 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Another Day's Journey: Correspondence, 2001 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Another Day's Journey: Contracts, 2001 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Another Day's Journey: Building Services, 2001 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Another Day's Journey: Budget, 2001 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Another Day's Journey: Audiovisual, 2001 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Blacks in Television, 1996 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Fighting for My Rights: Volunteers, 2000 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Fighting for My Rights: Task Analysis, 2000 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Fighting for My Rights: Security, 2000 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Fighting for My Rights: Program Proposal, 2000 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Fighting for My Rights: Press Releases, 2000 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Fighting for My Rights: Correspondence, 1999 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Fighting for My Rights: Panelists/Biographical Information, 1999 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Fighting for My Rights: Budget, 2000 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Fighting for My Rights: Contacts, 2000 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Fighting for My Rights: Audiovisual, 2000 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Press Releases, 1989-1992 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Spoken Word Conference, 2002 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Spoken Word Conference: Contacts/Biographies, 2002 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Spoken Word Conference: Scholars, 2001-2002 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Spoken Word Conference: Bibliography by Themes (Box 1 of 2)
  - National Conference on African American Gospel Music Scholarship, 1993 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Memory of African Culture performing Company (Box 1 of 2)
  - Niani Kilkenny: Correspondence, 1992 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Los Munequitos de Matanzas Concert, 1991-1992 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Los Munequitos de Matanzas Concert: Sponsors, 1992 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Los Munequitos de Matanzas Concert: Press Coverage, 1992 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Los Munequitos de Matanzas Concert: Press Releases, 1992 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Los Munequitos de Matanzas Concert: Program, 1992 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Los Munequitos de Matanzas Concert: Memoranda, 1992 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Los Munequitos de Matanzas Concert: Correspondence, 1992-1993 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Los Munequitos de Matanzas Concert: Budget, 1992 (Box 1 of 2)
  - W.E.B. DuBois Symposium: Participants Proposals, 2000 (Box 1 of 2)
  - W.E.B. DuBois Symposium: Acie Byrd, 1999-2000 (Box 1 of 2)
  - W.E.B. DuBois Symposium: Contact List, Registration, and Biographies, 2000 (Box 1 of 2)
  - W.E.B. DuBois Symposium: Correspondence, 2000 (Box 1 of 2)
  - W.E.B. DuBois Symposium: Correspondence with Ronald V. Dellums, 2000 (Box 1 of 2)
  - W.E.B. DuBois Symposium: Expenditures, 2000 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Program Web Page, 1995-1996 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Bibliographic Work, 1996 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Mind on Freedom: Abstracts of Papers, 1996 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Freedom Rides/Civil Rights Movement, 2000 (Box 1 of 2)
  - News Articles, 1995 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Martin Luther King, Jr., Commemoration Program, 1999 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Freedom Songs Relating to the Freedom Rides (Box 1 of 2)
  - Martin Luther King, Jr., Commemoration Program: Final Project, 2000 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Correspondence (general), 1999 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Middle Passage Conference: Travel Reports, 1999 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Middle Passage Conference: Elisee Soumonni, 1999 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Middle Passage Conference: Sound Checks, 1999 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Middle Passage Conference: Llewellyn Smith, 1999 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Middle Passage Conference: Special Events, 1998-1999 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Middle Passage Conference: Security, 1999 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Middle Passage Conference: Olafunmilayo Jomo, 1999 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Middle Passage Conference: Joseph E. Inikori, 1999 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Middle Passage Conference: Noel Ignatiev, 1999 (Box 1 of 2)
- Box 2
  - Middle Passage Conference: James O. Horton, 1999 (Box 2 of 2)
  - Hotel Morrison Clark, 1998-1999 (Box 2 of 2)
  - Middle Passage Conference: Sylvia I.B. Hill, 1998-1999 (Box 2 of 2)
  - Middle Passage Conference: Beverly Hill, 1999 (Box 2 of 2)
  - Middle Passage Conference: Leslie King Hammond, 1999 (Box 2 of 2)
  - Middle Passage Conference: Michael A. Gomez, 1999 (Box 2 of 2)
  - Middle Passage Conference: Haile Gerima, 1999 (Box 2 of 2)
  - Middle Passage Conference: C. Daniel Dawson, 1999 (Box 2 of 2)
  - Middle Passage Conference: Tom Feelings, 1999 (Box 2 of 2)
  - Middle Passage Conference: Adelaide M. Cromwell, 1999 (Box 2 of 2)
  - Middle Passage Conference: Houston Conwill, 1999 (Box 2 of 2)
  - Middle Passage Conference: Adama Conteh, 1999 (Box 2 of 2)
  - Community Letter, 1999 (Box 2 of 2)
  - Community Table, 1999 (Box 2 of 2)
  - Catering Director, 1999 (Box 2 of 2)
  - Middle Passage Conference: Kim D. Butler, 1999 (Box 2 of 2)
  - Victoria Botero, 1998-1999 (Box 2 of 2)
  - Middle Passage Conference: Michael Blakey, 1999 (Box 2 of 2)
  - Middle Passage Conference: Ronald W. Bailey, 1999 (Box 2 of 2)
  - Award Trophy, 1999 (Box 2 of 2)
  - Middle Passage Conference: Audiovisual, 1999 (Box 2 of 2)
  - Middle Passage Conference: African Heritage Drummers and Dancers, 1999 (Box 2 of 2)
  - Middle Passage Conference: Flyers, 1999 (Box 2 of 2)
  - UNESCO, 1998 (Box 2 of 2)
  - General Information re: Slavery, 1997 (Box 2 of 2)
  - Middle Passage Conference: Regrets, 1998 (Box 2 of 2)
  - Frozen in Black and White, 1998 (Box 2 of 2)
  - Exhibition: "We'll Never Turn Back," 1982 (Box 2 of 2)